SACHIN CHEJARA

QA Analyst

9887361562 | sachinchejara278@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sachin-kumar-978a64289 | Jaipur, Rajasthan

Summary

QA Test Engineer with experience in the field of Software Quality Assurance, testing Mobile applications, Web applications and having knowledge of all aspects of SDLC, STLC and defect tracking tools. Also, experience in working with Agile and expertise in developing test scenarios, preparing test data, creating bug documentation.

Skills

Manual TestingRegression TestingExploratory TestingDefect TrackingBlack Box TestingExtreme Accountability & Ownership

Highly Organized JIRA

Delivering positive customer engagement

Automation Testing(selenium with python)

My-SQL Postman for API Testing

Agile development using Scrum framework in JIRA Collaborative

Experience

Krishna Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Jhunjhunu

QA Analyst 07/2022 - 12/2022

Owebest Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

Jaipur

QA Analyst

03/2023 - Present

- Performed smoke test, sanity test, functional test, integration test, regression test
- Developed detailed functional and performance test cases and responsible for executing the test cases
- Create Test Plan, Test Strategy, Test Scenarios, Test Cases, test suite
- Responsible for read end-to-end user scenarios and create test cases
- Create Daily and Weekly test execution summary status report
- Create Defect Reports and participate in Defect Triage with developers
- Present weekly demos build walkthrough once in every week to client
- Onshore-Offshore Coordination with Client, DEV Team, BA, Scrum Master
- Carried out day to day duties accurately and efficiently
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed
- Worked flexible hours; night, weekend, and holiday shifts
- Performed automation testing by using selenium with python

Education

Mansarovar Global University

Bachelor of Computer Application (BCA)

2018 - 2021

Interests & Hobbies

Playing Cricket Football Listening Songs